Dear authors,


Thank you very much for your submission to the Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery journal.
Based on the advise of two reviewers, I can not recommend your paper for publication.
Most importantly, the novelty of the current submission over the DASFAA paper is unclear, and several important questions remain unanswered. I hope you will find the comments of the reviewers useful for your future research.

Sincerely,

Bart Goethals
Action Editor


Reviewer #1: SUMMARY.

This article is an extended version of an award-winning paper published at DASFAA 2014. The paper retains the merits of the conference version, presenting a solution for achieving rho-uncertainty while allowing for partial item suppression.
Yet it is not clear how this journal versions adds qualitatitvely to the conference version. One would expect such a journal extension to contain technical and theoretical material addressing questions that the conference version has left unanswered. In particular, the manuscripts should undergo a revision, in which is clarifies and discusses the following:

1. What is the worst-case complexity of the presented algorithms?
2. What are the correctness implications of allowing for partial suppressions? Can erroneous association rules be mined? What remedies are suggested for such side-effects?
3. How exactly does this version add to the conference version? (highlight added material in the paper)

RELEVANCE.
The paper is relevant to Data Mining and Knowledge Discovery.

SIGNIFICANCE
This paper has the potential to make a significant contribution in the area of inference-proof anonymization of set-valued data.

RELATED RESEARCH.
The paper is missing references to recent works in the line following on the models of k-anonymity and l-diversity, in particular to the models of t-closeness and beta-linkess.

RELATIONSHIP TO PREVIOUS RESEARCH
The relationship to the authors' own prior work should be further explained and highlighted.

THEORETICAL AND EXPERIMENTAL EVALUATION.
More discussions on the complexity of the proposed algorithms should be added.

EXPRESSION.
The paper is clearly written.

TECHNICAL DETAIL.
The technical details is sufficient, yet the contribution in relation to the conference version should be highlighted.

FURTHER COMMENTS:
As pointed out in point (2) above, the correctness of the whole exercise is vague. The authors should discuss how partial item suppression affects the correctness of support and confidence measures of derived rules. To show experimentally that some rules are preserved does not suffice in this journal version. A more elaborate discussion is required. It should be pondered that global suppression does not alter the support and confidence measures of those rules that are retained, while partial suppression does so. An honest discussion of this matter is necessary, along with the other points made above.


Reviewer #2: The paper presents a solution for anonymizing transaction databases using suppression. Previous suppression-based approaches adopt global-suppression, i.e., whenever they remove an item x from a transaction due to privacy concerns, they would also remove x from all other transactions. In contrast, the proposed algorithm adopts local-suppression, i.e., it allows an item x to be retained in a transaction even if the same item needs to be removed from another transaction. Experimental results in the paper show that the proposed algorithm improves over the existing methods. Nevertheless, I do not recommend acceptance, due to the following reasons.

First, the paper does not give a significant extension from its preliminary version published in DASFAA. All algorithms in the current paper are the same as those presented in the DASFAA work. The only things new, as the authors point out in Section 5, are that (a) the problem is formalized more rigorously, (b) more details of the algorithms are given, and (c) additional experiments are added. In other words, the current paper does not present any new technical contribution with respect to the preliminary version. Therefore, I feel that the paper does not satisfy the usual "30% extension" rule for extended papers.

Second, the proposed algorithms are rather ad hoc, with design choices made somewhat arbitrarily. For example, Algorithm 1 inserts transactions into a buffer in an arbitrary order, and sanitizes the buffer whenever it is full. The sanitization method (i.e., Algorithm 2) inspects unsafe associate rules in an arbitrary order, and removes items based on a heuristic. The heuristic does not even guarantee that the removal of items is always safe, as it may make some previously safe rules no longer safe; this issue is only addressed by recursively remove more items to suppress the newly induced unsafe rules, which does not seem elegant. Finally, the divide-and-conquer method in Algorithm 3 arbitrarily partitions the input data into several parts and anonymizes each part separately. Overall, I feel that the algorithms proposed in the paper are unrefined and are below the usual standard of DMKD.

Third, the paper does not compare the proposed solution with the differentially private algorithm proposed in [5], and does not explain why. As a consequence, it is unclear whether the proposed algorithm really advances the state of the art.

Fourth, the performance of the proposed algorithm is not very impressive. As shown in Figure 3, in datasets where 40% of the items are sensitive, the proposed algorithm needs to suppress 25%-40% of the items. This indicates that the algorithm is not too much better than a naïve approach that simply removes all sensitive items from the data.